What on earth is that thing…
那到底是什么东西？
Let's run!
我们快逃吧！
Wait!
等一下！
We might get killed.
说不定那家伙又会杀过来
What do you suggest we do then?
-那你说要怎么办才好？ -没有其他出口了吗？
How would I know?
我怎么会知道！
Two people are already dead.
都已经死两个人了啊！
Everyone, don't move!
全都不要动！
If we move rashly, the statue will attack again!
要是轻举妄动 石像会再度攻击！
Joohee…
珠熙
That was close.
好险啊
If you didn't notice the statue's movement,
如果不是你察觉到
we'd all be dead by now.
我们所有人早就死了
What?
什么？
You told us to get down because you knew it, right?
你不是知道才大叫 要我们趴下吗？
No.
不是的
I just sensed an imminent threat…
只是有种危险的预感…
Mr. Song!
宋大叔！你的手…
I can still bear it.
咬咬牙还是能撑过去
Can you help me stop the bleeding?
可以帮我止血吗？
I should have asked Joohee to treat me.
其实应该要请珠熙帮我治疗
But she's too weak-minded.
但是她的心灵太脆弱了
That's why despite being a B-rank healer,
这也是为什么她明明是B级治疗师 却只能参加简单的突击任务
I've also participated in a couple of B-rank missions.
我也参加过两三次B级任务
or even an S-rank one.
甚至是S级
The Commandments of the Cartenon Temple written on the stone are…
那个写在石板上的 凯勒特农神殿的戒律
"First, worship the God."
一是“敬拜神”
"Second, praise the God."
二是“赞美神”
"Third, believe the God."
三是“信仰神”
"Those who do not obey will not be able to leave this place alive."
凡不遵守戒律者 将无法活着离开此地
Mr. Song.
宋大叔 石板上所写的神
should be that, right?
应该就是那石像吧？
More than a decade ago,
距今十多年前
gates that could connect to a different dimension
世界上突然出现能够连接异次元 与这个世界的传送门
Abnormal phenomena kept occurring around the world.
各地开始发生颠覆常识的现象
For example, the Awakened are known as hunters.
被称为“猎人”的觉醒者现世 就是其中之一
Hunters are responsible for killing magic beasts in dungeons within the gates.
猎人肩负着重责大任
And after hunters awaken, their abilities will not change.
而猎人一旦得到能力 将不会出现任何改变
However, sometimes, on the other side of the gate,
然而有时在传送门的另一边
there are terrifying monsters that bring despair.
也会有恐怖至极
-Did you see that? -That film?
-你看那个了吗？ -你说那个视频吗？
Something came up.
有点事情
Jinah, your brother is a hunter, right?
珍雅的哥哥是猎人对吧？
But he's just an E-rank hunter.
不过他也只是个E级猎人
He always ends up being covered in wounds.
每次都搞得自己遍体鳞伤 感觉很辛苦
Last time he was covered in bandages.
上次还全身包着绷带呢
But why do you ask me this?
奇怪 你为什么要突然问我这个？
No reason.
没什么原因
If it were me, I wouldn't have ended up like that.
要是我 一定可以做得更好
We don't stand a chance.
对手太强了 我们敌不过
Let's get out once the situation settles down.
等状况稳定下来就找逃离的路线吧
-It might not be that easy-- -I can't die here!
-虽然可能没那么容易… -我怎么能坐以待毙啊！
I finally managed to sign a contract with a large association.
我好不容易才刚跟大型公会签了约
I can't die in this kind of place.
才不想死在这种鬼地方！
What are you doing? Don't move!
你做什么？不要乱动！
I'll finish it before it attacks.
在敌人动手前就能冲出去！
Damn it!
可恶！
It can finish us off at any time.
也就是说 只要石像有那个意思 随时都能解决我们所有人？
As easy as crushing an ant.
而且还是像踩扁一只虫子般容易
So why isn't it doing it now?
那它为何不现在就杀了大家？
It has the ability to kill us, but it isn't making a move.
明明能赶尽杀绝 却没有动手
It's different from those magic beasts that attack blindly.
跟那些看到人 就扑过来的魔兽有些不同
Mr. Song.
宋大叔 第一条戒律是什么？
Commandment?
戒律？
The first one is…
我记得第一条是…
"Worship the God."
“敬拜神”
God.
神…
This dungeon has its own rules.
这座地下城一有套自己的规则
W-What are you doing?
你要做什么？
Hey, stop it…
喂 住手！
You don't look like you're seeking death.
看你的眼神不像是要去送死的样子
Everyone!
各位 请朝那个石像跪拜！
Huh? Kneel to it?
什么？跪拜它？
What nonsense are you talking about?
你是在说什么傻话？
Did you figure out something?
你是不是明白了些什么？
Yes.
是的
As long as our heads are below a certain height, it won't attack.
看样子只要我们低着头 它就不会展开攻击
This is probably the meaning of the first commandment.
这应该就是“敬拜神” 这条戒律的意思
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
Yes, sort of…
是 算是吧
If so…
那样的话…
Can we really survive
真的只要做这种事就能活下来吗？
Its expression is terrifying.
好可怕的表情！
Its expression changed.
它的表情变了
It's not attacking us.
它什么都没做耶
Hey, if you move around…
喂 你要是乱动的话…
Look,
你们看！
it stopped attacking.
它停止攻击了！
Is it over just like that?
真的这样就结束了吗？
Are we saved?
-我们得救了吗？ -好耶
We made it.
-成功了 -太好了
-We're saved. -I can go back alive.
-得救了 -能活着回去了
No… It's not over yet.
不对 还没结束
It's not over?
难道还没结束吗？
Sung, what's next?
阿成 再来呢？
Can you think of something?
你应该有什么策略吧？
I… I don't know.
我没有什么策略啊
I think we can't violate the commandments here.
我只是觉得我们在这里 不能违反那些戒律
The second commandment is "Praise the God."
第二条戒律是“赞美神”
This is the clue.
那就是关键线索
Praise?
赞美？
How?
是要怎么做？
Leave it to me.
交给我来吧
I am conducting research on traditional folklore.
我曾做过传统民俗的研究
I know how to praise God.
我还记得赞颂神时该说什么话
Lord.
神啊
The ruler who brings order to the world.
为世界带来秩序的支配者啊
Any reaction?
-它有什么反应吗？ -请赐予光芒…
It seems to have slowed down…
-动作好像慢了一点 -照亮我弱小的内心
Guide me to the path of truth.
指引我通往真相的道路
Wait. This is…
等一下 这是…
I wish to follow the will of God.
神即为吾之所向
These are not the words to praise this god.
这些不是赞美此神的话语
We will worship and honor you.
我们将会献上崇拜和尊敬
Lord.
神啊
The ruler who brings order to the world.
为世界带来秩序的支配者啊…
-Damn it! -Run!
-可恶！ -快逃！
It's dangerous to be together.
聚在一起很危险 大家散开！
All right.
好
Joohee, run!
珠熙 快跑啊！
How can I die in a place like this?
我怎么能死在这种鬼地方！
My family is still waiting for me!
我的家人还在等我回家啊！
I should be safe here, right?
逃到这边就安全了吧？
Hey, Park, behind you!
喂 老朴 小心后面！
Park!
老朴！
"Praise the God…"
“赞美神”
What should we praise about it?
到底是要赞美那家伙的什么？
It's essentially a demon.
那根本就是恶魔啊
But…
可是…
I can't just abandon her.
我也不能丢下珠熙不管
Is there any clue…
有没有什么线索？
Spear.
枪、斧
My… my hand!
我的手！我的手啊！
Hammer.
槌子
Sword.
剑
Musical instrument.
乐器
Musical instrument…
乐器…
Everyone, get under the statue holding a musical instrument!
各位！
Musical instrument?
乐器？
It's playing?
它是在演奏吗？
The statue holding a musical instrument won't attack us!
喂 手拿乐器的石像不会攻击人！
Start playing quickly! Come on!
快点发出声音 快啊！
Two people can't stand here together?
难不成不能两个人一起站吗？
Joohee, stay here!
珠熙 你在这里不要动！
Jinwoo!
振宇！
Over there.
在那里！
Not there!
不是那边！
No!
不要啊！
Jinwoo!
振宇！
It's not over yet.
还没 还没完呢
Is this the answer to "Praise the God"?
这就是“赞美神”的答案吗？
Jinwoo!
振宇！
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
Yes. I'm fine.
没事 我还行
Jinwoo.
振宇
What is the matter?
怎么了？
Your foot…
你的脚…
It's enough, Joohee.
已经可以了 珠熙
I'm okay now.
我已经没事了
What are you talking about?
你在胡说什么？
I'll definitely cure you.
我一定会治好你的
Joohee.
珠熙
So tragic…
还真凄惨
Indeed.
就是啊
I'm very sorry that you lost your arm.
你失去手臂的事 我很遗憾
As the captain, you made a hasty decision.
但这都是因为你身为队长 却做出了草率的判断
This is karma.
这也算是报应
How cruel.
你太过分了
It's because Mr. Kim--
-当初还不是你说… -不是全员决定要进来的吗？
Indeed, it was me who made the final decision.
的确 最后做出决定的人是我
I must bear all the responsibility.
我必须负起全责
Now is not the time to argue.
现在根本不是争论的时候
There's still one commandment…
还有一条戒律的谜没有解开
What's happening this time?
这次又怎么了？
An earthquake?
是地震吗？
What is that?
那是什么？
An altar…
是祭坛
Doesn't it often appear in mythology?
神话里不是经常出现那种东西吗？
It's for offering tributes or living sacrifices to the god.
就是供奉神明时 放置宝物或活祭品的地方
The third commandment is "Believe the God."
第三条戒律是“信仰神”
I might be ignorant, but I know what this means.
就算我再怎么无知 也大概知道这是什么意思
Sung.
姓成的小兄弟
We need to offer a sacrifice, right?
这意思是我们得献上祭品对吧？
My companion, who bragged about his wife before departure, was cut in half.
出发前还在向我炫耀 他老婆的同伴被砍成了两半
There were others too.
还有好多人也丧命了
Do you remember what you just said?
你还记得刚刚说了什么吧？
Now it's your turn to take responsibility, Captain.
现在是你负责的时候了 队长
I understand.
我知道了
Let me go alone.
让我自己走过去吧
It's not just his fault.
这不是宋大叔一个人的错
We all voted to come in here.
我们明明是经过多数人的同意后 才决定要进来的啊
What's happening now?
现在是什么情况？
Sung.
阿成！
Is there something else I need to do?
我是不是还得再做什么？
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
Doesn't it want a living sacrifice?
难道它要的不是活祭品吗？
I'm sorry.
不好意思
I'd like to check the altar. Can you help me over there?
我想要去调查一下祭坛 你们能扶我过去吗？
Please take me near the altar.
麻烦带我去祭坛附近
But in this case…
可是这么一来…
I don't think anything will happen.
我想应该不会发生什么事
Have you figured out anything?
你知道些什么了吗？
No, not yet…
不 还不知道
If we wait here, will someone come to rescue us?
在这边等的话 会有人过来救我们吗？
Today is the seventh day after the dungeon was created.
传送门打开后到今天已经过了一周
I think they will take action before we are rescued.
我想在救兵抵达之前 那些家伙就会先有动作吧
The gate will be fully open after seven days.
传送门在七天后就会完全敞开
And that is Dungeon Break.
也就是地下城的“解除封印”
Then, the magic beasts will pass through the gate to the human world.
这么一来那些魔兽 就会穿越传送门 出去外面
That's why we must defeat the Boss and close the gate within the time limit.
为了防止这种状况发生 必须在时间内打倒头目 关闭传送门
This is another purpose of the raid mission.
这就是突击任务的另一个目标
If we fail here,
要是我们就此失败
it will run out into the world.
那东西就会跑到外面的世界去
Hello.
你好
Miss Sung.
嘿 成小姐
You come every day.
你每天都来 真是个好孩子
Mother, it's me again.
妈妈 我今天也来了喔
Let me tell you, Song-Yi was late today.
我跟你说喔 颂伊她今天迟到了
She said something kept her,
虽然她说有点事情
but she definitely overslept.
但她绝对是睡过头啦
And the last nationwide exam…
还有上次的全国考试…
Please come over here, you two.
两位也麻烦过来
This way, we should be able to light the corresponding number of flames.
这么一来应该会点起相应人数的火焰
Only then will we know what will happen.
石像一定会在那之后有动作
The door is open.
门打开了
Can we go out now?
可以出去了吗？
Could this be a trap…
这该不会也是陷阱吧？
What's that sound?
这次又是什么声音？
The… the statues are coming this way.
石像往这里走过来了！
What should we do?
我们该怎么办？
Why are they walking towards us?
那些家伙为什么会走过来？
No!
不要！
Joohee, don't close your eyes.
珠熙 不能闭上眼睛
Once we look away, they'll move closer.
一旦移开视线 它们就会靠过来
It's like the game we used to play as kids.
跟小时候玩过的游戏是一样的道理
Everyone must keep their eyes fixed on the statues.
所有人的视线不要离开石像！
No!
-不要！ -等一下！
Sung, what is this?
阿成 这是怎么回事？
The door closed a bit, but she made it out.
虽然门阖上了一点 但是她逃出去了
What's going on…
怎么回事？
The blue flames will go out over time.
蓝色火焰会随着时间消失
And once someone leaves the altar, the orange flames will also go out.
一旦有一个人离开祭坛 橘色火焰就会消失一个
The first commandment is "worship."
第一条戒律是“敬拜”
The second is "praise."
第二条是“赞美”
The third is "believe."
第三条则是“信仰”
That door must be a trap.
那扇门一定是陷阱
It offers false optimism to us who are in terror.
事实上充满恐怖与危险 只是让我们看见虚假的希望
Perhaps it tests our faith in God in this way.
或许就是用这种方式 来考验我们是否能坚持对神的信仰
I-I'm sorry.
抱歉
I can't hold on any longer.
我撑不下去了
-Jungho! -Hey!
-正浩！ -喂！
No!
不可以！
Everyone, don't move!
不要动！
If anyone else leaves, it will create a blind spot!
再有人离开的话 视线会产生死角的
Sung, what does this mean?
阿成 这是什么意思？
Explain it!
快说明一下！
Just keep it this way, and don't move your gaze away from the statue.
只要维持这个样子 别将视线从石像移开就行了
The blue flame is a timer.
蓝色火焰是定时器
When it goes out completely, everyone should be able to escape.
等到火焰完全熄灭 所有人应该就能脱身
But, Sung…
但是啊 小兄弟
It's also possible that when the flame goes out completely, we'll be locked up.
也有可能是火焰完全熄灭时 我们就会被关起来吧
To be honest,
老实说
I never thought that you would be so capable as the weakest one.
我完全没想到实力最弱的你 居然会在此大显身手
We can survive until now
我们之所以能捡回一条小命
all thanks to you.
都是多亏了有你在
Mr. Kim…
金大叔
But you see,
但是啊 也有家人在等我
I don't want to die yet.
我还不想死
I want to go home alive.
我想要活着回去
I can't hold on any longer.
我也已经撑不下去了
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Why…
为什么？
I must survive.
我一定要活下去
I have always survived this way.
我一直都是这样活过来的
You two, leave quickly.
你们两个快走吧
I think as long as one person stays, that door won't close.
我想只要留下一个人 那扇门应该就不会完全关上
Then I should let the young people with promising futures leave first.
那就应该要让还有长远未来的 年轻人得救才对
Joohee, take Sung with you.
珠熙 阿成就拜托你照顾了
Okay!
好的
Strange…
什么？奇怪
You've overexerted yourself when treating Sung.
看来你为了帮阿成治疗 太过勉强自己了
Mr. Song.
宋大叔 你带珠熙逃离吧
What? I said I would stay--
什么？我不是说要留下来吗？
Then who will help Joohee out?!
那么谁要扶珠熙出去？
There's no time, hurry up!
没时间了 动作快
No… Jinwoo…
不可以 振宇！
Let me stay!
不如由我留下来吧！
I promised I would take you out to eat, right?
我答应过要请你吃饭对吧？
Use this to buy something to eat.
你就拿这个先去吃吧
After I get out,
等我离开这里后
I'll come to you for the rest of the money.
我会去找你要剩下的钱
How can you still joke--
都这种时候了 你还跟我开玩笑…
I'm sorry.
抱歉
We're really running out of time.
好像真的没时间了
-I'll leave her in your care. -All right.
麻烦你了
Great.
太好了
Luckily, I'm the only one who's going to die.
幸好要死的人只有我
If I had known,
早知道会这样
I would have bought more insurance.
保险就保多一点了
At least one of you will have to accompany me on the way.
至少要你们其中一个陪我一起上路
Come at me!
放马过来吧！
I'm always the weakest.
无论何时 我都是最弱的
People around me always keep ridiculing me.
身边的人总是不断嘲笑我
But I've tried my best to make it through.
但我还是咬着牙撑了过来
And yet…
但是…
Are you kidding me…
开什么玩笑！
Are you kidding me?!
开什么玩笑
I wanted to become stronger too.
我也想要变强啊
But I couldn't.
然而我却办不到
Despite that,
即便如此
I've survived up to now in my own way.
我还是用自己的方法努力活到了现在
Are you--
开什么…
You can't hold on anymore?
说什么“撑不下去”？
We're all suffering!
大家不是都一样吗？
You're just justifying yourself!
到头来你只是 想将自己的作为正当化而已！
All the gratitude is just lip service.
什么感谢的话语都是说好听的
It's always the selfish ones who get all the benefits!
得到好处的 永远都是最为自己着想的人！
I have a family too.
我也有家人啊
I want to return home alive too!
我也想活着回去啊！
"Luckily, I'm the only one who's going to die"?
“幸好要死的人只有我”？
Stop it, hypocrite.
别蠢了 伪善的家伙！
Don't…
不要
I don't want to die.
我不想死
If…
要是…
If I could have another chance…
如果能再给一次机会…